A Guide to the Papers of Floyd E. Johnson 1938-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Papers of Floyd E. Johnson 1953-1999
  - Photographs - Williamsburg, Virginia (with Negatives) n.d. (Box 9)
  - Projects - Albemarle County Courthouse 1968-1989, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Projects - Albemarle County Courthouse 1983 Sep 9, 3 folders (Box 10)
    Specifications
  - Projects - Mr. and Mrs. Richard D. Anderson, North Garden House, Albemarle County, Virginia 1976 Jan 1 (Box 11)
  - Projects - Archaeological Survey Materials n.d. (Box 11)
  - Projects - Ash Lawn, Albemarle County, Virginia 1989 Feb 21 (Box 11)
    Wood, Sweet, and Swofford Team Proposal
  - Projects - Belle Grove, Albemarle County, Virginia (Valmont) 1983-1987, n.d. (Box 11)
    Kitchen
  - Projects - Belle Grove, Albemarle County, Virginia (Valmont) 1944-1989, n.d. (Box 11)
    Notes
  - Projects - Belle Grove, Albemarle County, Virginia (Valmont) 1968-1994 (Box 11)
    Sketches, Plans, etc.
  - Projects - Belle Grove, Albemarle County, Virginia (Valmont) 1979 Jun 4 (Box 11)
    Specifications for Mr. and Mrs. E. Sykes Scherman
  - Projects - Boar's Head Inn, Albemarle County, Virginia 1889-1990 (Box 11)
  - Projects - James Brown Hermitage 1991 (Box 11)
    Sketches
  - Projects - William Buchardt House, Post Oak, Virginia 1988-1990 (Box 11)
    Notes and Sketches
  - Projects - Burning Daylight Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Arthur A. Watson, Jr. 1989 Sep (Box 11)
    Foal Stables - Project Manual
  - Projects - Burning Daylight Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Arthur A. Watson, Jr. 1994-1996 (Box 11)
    House
  - Projects - Burning Daylight Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Arthur A. Watson, Jr 1987-1988 Sep (Box 11)
    Notes, Sketches, etc.
  - Projects - Burning Daylight Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Arthur A. Watson, Jr. 1988 Oct - 1991, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Projects - Burning Daylight Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Arthur A. Watson, Jr. 1986-1989, n.d., 2 folders (Box 12)
    Stables
  - Projects - Capitol Square, Richmond, Virginia 1952-1974, n.d. (Box 12)
    Report the Virginia Department of Highways, etc.
  - Projects - Cherry Hill Estate, Albemarle County, Virginia 1993, n.d. (Box 12)
    Sale and Sketch
  - Projects - Christ Church, Glendower, St. Anne's Parish, Albemarle County, Virginia 1958-1995, n.d. (Box 12)
    Cemetary Committee, House Tour, etc.
  - Projects - Christ Church, Glendower, St. Anne's Parish, Albemarle County, Virginia 1991-1994 (Box 12)
    Finance Committee
  - Projects - Christ Church, Glendower, St. Anne's Parish, Albemarle County, Virginia 1957-1994, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Projects - Christ Church, Glendower, St. Anne's Parish, Albemarle County, Virginia 1957-1994, n.d. (Box 12)
    Notes, Printed Materials, Pamphlets
  - Projects - Christ Church, Glendower, St. Anne's Parish, Albemarle County, Virginia 1981 Oct 19 (Box 12)
  - Projects - Cismont Manor Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Wheeler 1990-1997, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Projects - Cocke's Mill House (Tsuquatantia), Albemarle County, Virginia, Dr. David L. Morris 1985, 1989, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Projects - Derwent, Powhatan County, Virginia 1947-1968, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Projects - Details - Sketches ca. 1948-1993, n.d., 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Projects - Fairfax Hall, Waynesboro, Virginia 1994, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Projects - Fluvanna County Courts and Public Facilities Proposal 1992 Jul 9 (Box 13)
  - Projects - Robert Y. Frazier House [Sherwood Hill?], Harrisonburg, Virginia 1985, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Projects - Gallison Hall, James F. Scott 1992-1993 (Box 13)
  - Projects - Glen Echo, Albemarle County, Virginia 1988-1990 (Box 13)
    Bridges and Landscaping
  - Projects - Glen Echo, Albemarle County, Virginia 1987-1992, n.d., 2 folders (Box 13)
    Kitchen, Pantry, Laundry, Bath, etc.
  - Projects - Glen Echo, Albemarle County, Virginia n.d. (Box 13)
    Logo
  - Projects - Glen Echo, Albemarle County, Virginia 1987 (Box 13)
    Materials (Hardware, Brick, etc.)
  - Projects - Glen Echo, Albemarle County, Virginia 1987-1990 (Box 13)
    Notes, Schedules, etc.
  - Projects - Glen Echo, Albemarle County, Virginia 1988-1990 (Box 14)
    Pool House
  - Projects - Wayne Goodall n.d. (Box 14)
  - Projects - Hatton Ferry Committee, Albemarle County Historical Society 1982-1987 (Box 14)
  - Projects - Residence of John A. Herdeg, Mendenhall, Chester County, Pennsylvania (William Peters House) 1992 (Box 14)
  - Projects - Horseshoe Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mrs. Harold B. Alexander 1990-1995 (Box 14)
  - Projects - House Plans - Unidentified 1966-1980 (Box 14)
  - Projects - Index to Projects by Johnson, Craven, and Gibson and a brochure describing selected projects n.d. (Box 14)
  - Projects - Residence for Pat and Alex Janssen 1991 (Box 14)
  - Projects - Jefferson-Madison Regional Library - Crozet 1980, 1984, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Projects - Lanigan and Associates, Thomasville, Georgia 1983-1990 (Box 14)
  - Projects - Lanigan and Associates, Thomasville, Georgia 1990 (Box 14)
    Project Manual
  - Projects - Lanigan And Associates, Thomasville, Georgia 1982 (Box 14)
  - Projects - Madison County Courthouse 1953-1976 (Box 14)
    Notes, Sketeches, Plans, etc.
  - Projects - James H.T. McConnell, Jr. Residence, [Rapidan?] Virginia 1992 (Box 15)
  - Projects - McIntire Library, Albemarle County, Virginia 1993 (Box 15)
    Alterations and Additions - Project Manual
  - Projects - O. Leland Mahan Residence, Leesburg, Virginia 1977, 1996 (Box 15)
  - Projects - Martha Jefferson Hospital and Sanatorium, Inc. Alterations and Additions 1973 (Box 15)
  - Projects - Mill House, Scottsville, Virginia, for Floyd E. Johnson and Anne H. Johnson 1964, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Projects - Miscellaneous Details and Notes 1939-1992, n.d., 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Projects - Captain and Mrs. Robert Miyagawa Residence, Shores, Virginia 1976 Sep 1 (Box 15)
  - Projects - Mirador, Albemarle County, Virginia, John Burghardt - Kennel 1993-1996 (Box 15)
    Notes, Photographs, and Sketches
  - Projects - Mirador, Albemarle County, Virginia, John Burghardt - Kennel 1993 (Box 15)
  - Projects - Miscellaneous Details and Notes 1939-1992, n.d., 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia 1984, n.d. (Box 15)
    Archaeology
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia 1976-1983, n.d. (Box 15)
    Brick
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Dome Room 1955-1987 (Box 15)
    Sketches, etc.
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Dome Room 1988-1990, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - First House 1986, n.d. (Box 16)
    Notes, Plans, etc.
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Garden Pavilion 1976-1984, n.d. (Box 16)
    Materials - Bricks, Metal Roofing, etc.
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Garden Pavilion 1979-1982, n.d. (Box 16)
    Plans, Specifications, etc.
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Garden Pavilion 1981-1991, n.d. (Box 16)
    South Garden Walk and Plans for Paling
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Gift Shop 1983-1989, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - House 1975-1986, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia 1987 Spring (Box 16)
    Jefferson and Monticello, a University of Virginia Continuing Education Class
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Levy Tomb, Mulberry Row, and Stone House 1984, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Mary Wingfield Scott Award for Preservation 1988 (Box 16)
    Virginia Society of the American Institute of Architects Honors Committee Proposal to Honor the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Miscellaneous 1942-1988, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Observation Tower 1986, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Observatory 1986 (Box 17)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Roofing and Skylights 1981-1989 (Box 17)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Steps from Mulberry Row to Garden 1989-1990, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Projects - Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia - Walk Lighting 1985-1986, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Projects - Monticello - Wood Details 1981-1982 (Box 17)
  - Projects - Monticola, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Cynthia Littlejohn and Edward Silvermand 1993-1994 (Box 17)
    Notes and Specifications
  - Projects - Montpelier, Orange County, Virginia 1993 Apr 23 (Box 17)
    Pony Barn - Proposal
  - Projects - Montpelier, Orange County, Virginia 1990 Jun (Box 17)
    Viewing Stand
  - Projects - Mount Ida, Albemarle County, Albemarle 1996-1997 (Box 17)
    for James Brady Murray, who had it moved from Buckingham County
  - Projects - Moyer House, Crozet, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Richard W. Moyer 1981 Jan (Box 17)
  - Projects - News Clippings 1951-1992 (Box 17)
  - Projects - Old Town Farm, for Charles C. Lewis 1983-1987, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Projects - Peaks of Otter Motel, Blue Ridge Parkway 1963
  - Projects - Piedmont Virginia Community College 1984 Mar 6 (Box 17)
    Proposal and Scope of Consulting Services
  - Projects - Plain Dealing Farm, Keene, Virginia, for Philippe de Villegas 1990 (Box 17)
  - Projects - Plumb House and Property, Waynesboro, Virginia n.d. (Box 17)
    Proposal
  - Projects - Poindexter House, Waynesboro, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Gordon W. Poindexter, Jr. 1974 (Box 17)
    Schematics
  - Projects - Powhatan Plantation, King George, Virginia, for Mrs. Carolin Guest 1994 (Box 17)
  - Projects - Resumes of Other Architects 1988-1990 (Box 18)
  - Projects - Rockefeller Residence and Conservatory, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Dori Rockefeller 1988, n.d. (Box 18)
    Notes and Photographs
  - Projects - Alterations and Additions for Round Hill, for Mr. and Mrs. William O. Bourke 1990 (Box 18)
  - Projects - St. Luke's Episcopal Church, Powhatan County, Virginia 1996 (Box 18)
  - Projects - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1954, 10 copies of Field Notes (Box 18)
    Archaeological Exploration Report and Field Notes by Paul J.F. Schumacher
  - Projects - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1955, 4 copies of report (Box 18)
    Arcaheaological Exploration Report by Roland W. Robbins
  - Projects - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1954-1993 (Box 18)
    Articles
  - Projects - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1954-1984 (Box 18)
    General Information and Sketches
  - Projects - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1959-1995 (Box 18)
    Peter Jefferson's House - Notes, Sketches and prints of original plans
  - Projects - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1958 Aug (Box 18)
    Peter Jefferson's House- Specifications
  - Projects - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1972-1973, n.d. (Box 18)
    Jefferson's Old Mill
  - Projects - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1955 (Box 18)
    Statements
  - Projects - Stonewall jackson House, Lexington, Virginia 1979 (Box 18)
  - Projects - Stuarts Cemetary and Stuart Manor Farm, Lewisburg, West Virginia, for Mrs. Turner Rust Ratrie 1976-1983, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Projects - Tallwood, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Peggy Van Clief 1989 (Box 18)
  - Projects - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1984, n.d. (Box 18)
    Lighting for Liberty Bell Replica at the Charlottesville Fire House on Ridge Street
  - Projects - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1983 (Box 18)
    Visitor's Center
  - Projects - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1985 Jun (Box 19)
    Visitor's Center - Interpretive Plan
  - Projects - Time Records 1991-1995, n.d., 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Projects - Tri-County Riding Club 1989 (Box 19)
  - Projects - Tuckahoe Plantation, near Richmond, Virginia 1955 (Box 19)
  - Projects - Unidentified Sketches 1980, 1986, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Projects - University of Virginia 1950-1972, 1898 (Box 19)
  - Projects - University of Virginia 1981 (Box 19)
    East Range
  - Projects - University of Virginia 1984 (Box 19)
    Lawn Improvements - Specifications
  - Projects - University of Virginia 1985 (Box 19)
    Madison Hall Renovation Phase II
  - Projects - University of Virginia 1985-1987 (Box 19)
    Miller Center of Public Affairs
  - Projects - University of Virginia 1969-1979 (Box 20)
    North Grounds Landscape Committee
  - Projects - University of Virginia 1983 (Box 20)
    Rotunda Esplanade Renovation - Proposal and Specifications
  - Projects - Whippoorwill Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Dr. and Mrs. Douglas Nicoll 1955, 1990 (Box 20)
    Plans and Sketches
  - Projects - White Hall Farm, Gloucester, Virginia 1995 (Box 20)
  - Research Files - American Institute of Architects 1977, 1987 (Box 20)
    Forms
  - Research Files - Bellair Plantation n.d. (Box 20)
  - Research Files - Belle Grove (Valmont), Albemarle County, Virginia 1935, 1975, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Research Files - Buildings; Art, Renderings, and Print 1931-1987, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Research Files - Building Codes and Regulations for Virginia 1980-1981 (Box 20)
  - Research Files - Charlottesville, Virginia 1942-1975, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Research Files - Chimneys n.d. (Box 20)
    Primitive and Historic
  - Research Files - Contract Specifications Format 1970-1986 (Box 20)
  - Research Files - Details ca. 1916-1985, n.d. (Box 21)
    Fences, Rails, and Gates
  - Research Files - Details n.d. (Box 21)
    Furniture
  - Research Files - Details 1990, n.d. (Box 21)
    Lighting
  - Research Files - Details n.d. (Box 21)
    Mantels
  - Research Files - Details 1955, n.d. (Box 21)
    Signs
  - Research Files - Details n.d. (Box 21)
    Stairs and Ladders
  - Research Files - Edgemont, Albemarle County, Virginia n.d. (Box 21)
  - Research Files - Esmont Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia n.d. (Box 21)
  - Research Files - Ferries in the United States 1983-1984, n.d. (Box 21)
    particularly the Hatton Ferry on the James River in Virginia
  - Research Files - Fire Code Information 1970-1982, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Research Files - Hardware and Decorative Metalwork 1934-1990, n.d., 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Research Files - Heating and Ventilation 1962-1982, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Research Files - Historic Buildings 1955-1989, n.d. (Box 21)
    Newspaper clippings
  - Research Files - House Designs 1930-1987, n.d., 2 folders (Box 21)
    including interiors
  - Research Files - Landscaping and Gardens 1949-1992, n.d. (Box 22)
  - Research Files - Log Cabins and Outbuildings and Other Log Structures 1989, n.d. (Box 22)
  - Research Files - Long Branch, Clark County, Virginia 1955, 1986, n.d. (Box 22)
  - Research Files - Miscellaneous 1955-1990, n.d. (Box 22)
  - Research Files - Monroe Doctrine n.d. (Box 22)
  - Research Files - Monticello 1975-1989, n.d. (Box 22)
  - Research Files - Monticello 1984-1991, n.d. (Box 22)
    Brochures and Postcards
  - Research Files - Monticello 1959, 1982, n.d. (Box 22)
    Dome of Glass
  - Research Files - Monticello 1913, 1983-1984, n.d. (Box 22)
    Garden Pavilion
  - Research Files - Monticello 1954-1990, n.d. (Box 22)
    Jefferson, Palladio, and Hadrian's Pantheon
  - Research Files - Monticello and Jefferson 1978-1993, n.d. (Box 22)
    News clippings
  - Research Files - Mouldings 1977-1987, n.d. (Box 22)
  - Research Files - Nails 1939-1977, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Research Files - National People's Bank n.d. (Box 23)
  - Research Files - Orangery, Greenhouses, or Conservatories 1973-1992, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Research Files - Paint 1942-1985, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Research Files - Paint Color Samples n.d. (Box 23)
  - Research Files - Paint ca. 1970-1985, n.d. (Box 23)
    Williamsburg Colors
  - Research Files - Plain Dealing Plantation, Albemarle County, Virginia n.d. (Box 23)
  - Research Files - Preservation and Restoration 1949-1990, n.d., 4 folders (Box 23)
  - Research Files - Roofing 1914-1982, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Research Files - Shadwell, Albemarle County, Virginia 1945, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Research Files - Structure 1974-1987, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Research Files - The Swan House, Atlanta, Georgia n.d. (Box 24)
  - Research Files - United States Capitol 1952-1964, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Research Files - University of Virginia 1961-1988, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Research Files - University of Virginia 1961-1988, n.d. (Box 24)
    Rotunda
  - Research Files - Waterford, Loudoun County, Virginia 1972 (Box 24)
  - Research Files - Williamsburg, Virginia ca. 1955-1963, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Research Files - Wood Designs and Products 1981, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Selected Work of Floyd E. Johnson, FAIA ca. 1995 (Box 24)
  - Slides - Alaska and Western Trip 1984 Aug, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Slides - Architectural Sketches and Drawings 1974, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Slides - Brookwood School, Thomasville, Georgia n.d. (Box 25)
  - Slides - Cherry Hill Estate, Albemarle County, Virginia 1989-1990 (Box 25)
  - Slides - Crozet Library, Albemarle County, Virginia 1984 (Box 25)
  - Slides - Glendower, Albemarle County, Virginia 1989-1990 (Box 25)
  - Slides - Glen Echo, Albemarle County, Virginia 1989-1990 (Box 25)
  - Slides - Greece 1965 (Box 25)
  - Slides - Miscellaneous Projects ca. 1979-1989, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Slides - Monticello 1982-1989 (Box 25)
  - Slides - Personal ca. 1964-1990, n.d., 5 folders (Box 26)
  - Slides - Personal ca. 1966-1985, n.d., 5 folders (Box 27)
  - Slides - Personal 1984-1990, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Slides - Piedmont Virginia Community College 1971, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Slides - Russia 1989, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Artifacts n.d. (Box 28)
    Mortar and Brick Samples from the Garden Pavilion at Monticello and Nails from Belle Grove, Albemarle County, and the Stonewall Jackson House in Lexington, Virginia
  - Two Scrapbooks ca. 1930-1950 (Box 28)
    Clippings of Details and Buildings belonging to Floyd E. Johnson
- Series II: Architectural Drawings, Sketches, Artwork, Awards, and Diplomas 1930-1998
  - Awards, Citations, Certificates, etc of Floyd Johnson 1932-1998, 15 items (Oversize 1)
    Pertaining to Varsity Letters at the University of Virginia in Track; his membership on the Virginia Art Commission; the Thomas Jefferson Society of Alumni; Civic league Chorlottesville and Albemarle County Citation of Merit; the American Institue of Architects Certificate of Fellowship; License to Pratice Architecture in West Virginia; Certificate of Appreciation from the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundations, Inc; the Virginia Society of the American Institute of Architects Award for Preservation; Lifetime Achievement Award for outstanding service in Historic Preservation from the Thomas Jefferson Branch of the Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities
  - Prints and Miscellaneous Sketches 1993-1994, n.d., 20 items (Oversize 2)
    of George Washington and Thomas Jefferson; of Louis Ballou Watercolors
  - Archtectural Details, 75 items (Oversize 3)
    Drawings of Lighting Fixtures
  - Architectural Details, 50 items (Oversize 4)
    Pictures of Lighting Fixtures
  - Unidentified Architectural Drawings 1972-1997, n.d., 75 items (Oversize 5)
  - Unidentified Architectural Drawings 1959, n.d., 30 items (Oversize 6)
    Details
  - Architectural Drawings ca. 1988-1996, 50 items (Oversize 7)
    Burning Daylight Farm, Albemarle County, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Arthur A. Watson, Jr.
  - Architectural Drawings 1963, n.d., 7 items (Oversize 8)
    Castle Hill, Cherry Hill, and Derwent
  - Architectural Drawings, 8 items (Oversize 9)
    Faulkner House, University of Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1984, 3 items (Oversize 10)
    Hennage House, Williamsburg, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1991, 2 items (Oversize 11)
    Residence for John and Judy Herdeg, Hillendale Road, Mendenhall, Chester County, Pennsylvania
  - Architectural Drawings 1988-1990, 5 items (Oversize 12)
    Horseshoe Farm, for Mrs. Harold B. Alexander
  - Architectural Drawings 1983-1998, 11 items (Oversize 13)
    Indian Trace Farm, Locust Dale, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Stephen Murphy; the George Jackson Memorial, Albemarle County; and the Hermitage for Jim Brown
  - Architectural Drawings 1956-1982, 10 items (Oversize 14)
    Miscellaneous Renderings, chiefly mounted on boards, including Alterations to the Former Daily Progress Complex; Piedmont Virginia Community College (photograph of rendering); The People's National Bank Loan Department; House for Mr. and Mrs. Truman Dodson; 3 Studies for Ednam Forest; Alterations to Donegal for Mr. and Mrs. Pierson Scott; and unidentified
  - Architectural Drawings 1957-1989, n.d., 55 items (Oversize 15)
    Monticello and Related
  - Architectural Drawings 1970-1994, 48 items (Oversize 16)
    Monticello (cont); Monticola; St. Anne's Parish; and Proposed Revision for master Site Plan, Shadwell; State Capitol Area, Richmond, Virginia; Tufton Barn
  - Architectural Drawings 1995, 15 items (Oversize 17)
    Prints of rendersings for the House and Grounds of White Hall Farm, Gloucester, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Peter Hunt
  - Architectural Drawings, 20 items (Oversize 18)
    Lighting Details, mounted on boards
  - Architectural Drawings, 25 items (Oversize 19)
    Lighting Details, chiefly mounted on boards
  - Architectural Drawings 1967-1993, n.d., 55 items (Oversize 20)
    Unidentified
  - Architectural Drawings 1950, n.d., 6 items (Oversize 21)
    Unidentified, mounted on boards
  - University of Virginia Diploma of Floyd Johnson 1934 (Oversize 22)
    BS in Architecture
  - Architectural Drawings 1960-1989, 18 items (Oversize 23)
    Some mounted on boards - Albemarle County Courthouse Addition; Blair House Restaurant; Bath County Cooperative Library; Burning Daylight Farm
  - Architectural Drawings 1937-1997, n.d., 24 items (Oversize 24)
    some mounted on boards - W.S. Butterfield Servant's House; Chirst Church, Glendower; Christmas Hill Club House, Albemarle County, Virginia; Cismont Manor Farm for Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Wheeler; Farmington House for Dr. M. Marcy, George B. Ferry Real Estate
  - Architectural Drawings 1955-1989, 31 items (Oversize 25)
    some mounted on boards - Glen Echo Farm; Glendower interiors (photographs) and Details; Gristmill Square, Warm Springs, Virginia, for Mr. and Mrs. Philip Hirsch; Porch for Mr. and Mrs. John T. Hjorth, Carter's Bridge, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1968-1997, n.d., 21 items (Oversize 26)
    some mounted on boards - Study of Residence for Mr. amd Mrs. M.C. Jennings, Columbus, Georgia; Lanigan and Associates, Thomasville, Georgia; Madison County Courthouse, Madison, Virginia; McConnell Residence; [Monticello?]; Mount Ida; Mount Moriah Methodist Church
  - Architectural Drawings and Renderings 1950-1994, n.d. (Oversize 11 items)
    some mounted on boards - Study of People's National Bank, Elkton Branch; Study of Residence for Mr. and Mrs. H.L. Petty, Albemarle County, Virginia; Piedmont Virginia Community College Roof for Ceramic Kiln; Proposed Scottsville Water Facility Improvement; House for Mr. and Mrs. S.P. Semmes; Weathervane for Mr. and Mrs. Sykes Scherman, Albemarle County, Virginia; St. John's Church, Scottsville, Virginia
  - Architectural Drawings 1954-1972, n.d., 7 items (Oversize 28)
    some mounted on boards - Residence of Mr. and Mrs. William T. Stevens, Bellair, Albemarle County, Virginia; Virginia National Bank, Charlottesville, Virginia; Virginia Stage Lines, Inc., Terminal Building, Charlottesville, Virginia; Westminster Presbyterian CHurch, Sunday School Building, Charlottesville, Virginia; Gordon Wiley, Shop Front, Charlottesville, Virginia; and [?] Tavern
  - Architectural Drawings 1930-1995, n.d., 6 items (Oversize 29)